なんで…｡
お前の居場所は
ここじゃねえだろ？
私 絶対 帰らないね｡
よく考えろよ｡
(銀時)帰れ…｡
ちょっと待って！
やめろ!!
ずっと…
ずっと銀ちゃんたちと…｡
いい機会だ…
親父と一緒に行けよ｡
お前には やっぱり
地球は狭いんじゃねえの？
なんで… なんで…｡
これで さよならとしようや｡
(神楽)なんで…
なんで そんなこと言うね｡
♪♪～
Go home.
The Earth's too small for you, after all.
I think we can all see that now. Go home with your father.
Let's make this good-bye.
What? Why? Why are you saying that?
I'm never going back...
I'll stay...forever...with you and the others...
Wait...
Stop it!
Think about it. This isn't where you belong, is it?
Why...?
[Umibozu, Kagura's father, visited Earth to retrieve his daughter.]
[Gintoki fired Kagura and she has decided to leave the Earth.]
["You Can't Judge a Movie by Its Title"]
(雨音)
((悪党:ﾌﾌﾌ… お嬢ちゃん｡
Young lady, what're you doing in a place like this?
(悪党)どうしたんだい？
こんなところで…｡
(悪党)
おじさんたちと一緒に来ない？
Why don't you come with us?
おじさんたちはね ｷﾐのような
身寄りのない子を引き取って➡
We take good care of little girls like you.
新しい親に売り飛ばす➡
We'll even sell you to new parents! We're very kind men, you know.
それは それは
優しい おじさんたちなんだよ～！
(悪党たちの笑い声)
(悪党)お嬢ちゃん…｡
Young lady...
(星海坊主)お嬢さん
どうしたんだい？ こんな所で｡
Young lady, what're you doing in a place like this?
(星海坊主)
こんな日に 傘もささないで｡
And without your umbrella on a day like this.
(神楽)今日は 雨だからいいね｡
It's raining today, so I don't need it.
(星海坊主)そりゃ おかしい｡
Don't be ridiculous. Umbrellas are supposed to be for rainy days.
傘とは 本来
雨をしのぐために さすもんだ｡
雨の日まで 傘さしてたら➡
If I opened my umbrella on a rainy day, I'd never be able to see the sky.
いつまでたっても
空を おがめないね｡
雨空でもいいから
私も 空をおがみたいね｡
I want to see the sky, even if it's raining.
(星海坊主)ﾌﾝ… 風邪ひくぞ！
Hmm... You'll catch cold.
Pappy!
(神楽)ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ！))
It was a dreary city of constant rain...
＜星海坊主:一年じゅう
雨ばかり降る ｼﾞﾒｼﾞﾒした街｡
そこが ｵﾚたちの巣だった｡
That was our home.
日陰でしか生きられない連中が
集まる 魔窟｡
A place where only the unscrupulous could survive.
はたから見れば 汚いﾄﾞﾌﾞ川でも➡
Others may have seen it as a sewer canal of a place,
ﾄﾞﾌﾞﾈｽﾞﾐには
住みやすい場所だった＞
but it was a great place to live for sewer rats.
Pappy, when will you come home next?
((神楽:ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ！
次は いつ帰ってくるね？
(星海坊主)今 帰ったとこなのに
もう そんな話か｡
I just got home and you're already asking me that?
Don't leave anymore, Pappy.
(神楽)もう行かないでよ ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ｡
私 もう 一人で
ﾏﾐｰの苦しむ姿 見たくないよ｡
I don't want to see Mommy so sad anymore.
兄ちゃんも帰ってこないし
ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰも帰ってこない｡
Big brother doesn't come home, and you rarely come home.
私 寂しいね｡
I'm lonely.
(星海坊主)かあちゃんの病気も
きっと もうすぐ よくなる｡
Your mother's illness will get better soon, I'm sure.
(星海坊主)兄ちゃんも
もうすぐ帰ってくる｡
Your older brother will be back soon, as well.
Until then, I have to make money and you have to watch over your mother.
それまで ｵﾚが 金を稼いで
お前は かあちゃんを守る｡
そう約束しただろ？))
That was our promise.
＜星海坊主:そう言って ｱｲﾂを➡
How many times did I say that to her... Only to leave her in that hellhole, over and over again...
あの汚いﾄﾞﾌﾞ川に
何度 残していったことだろう｡
それでもｱｲﾂは ﾀﾞﾒ親父の帰りを➡
And yet, she was always waiting... Always with a smile for her no-good father.
何度 笑って迎えてくれただろう｡
結局 かあちゃんが死ぬまで
その繰り返し｡
In the end, we just kept repeating this scene until her mother died.
ｵﾚは ｱｲﾂに 一度も温かい巣なんて
つくってやれなかった＞
I never once...was able to make a warm nest for her.
That's why you came to this distant place to find your nest...
《星海坊主:だから お前は
こんな遠いところまで➡
巣なんか
探しに来ちまったんだな…》
(星海坊主)もうすぐ出るぞ｡
We're taking off soon. Get ready to go, Kagura-chan.
そろそろ準備しておけ
神楽ちゃん｡
How cold of them.
(星海坊主)薄情なもんだな｡
しばらく一緒にいたってのに➡
You're with them all this time, and they don't even come to see you off.
見送りにも来やがらねえ！
(星海坊主)結局 あれか…
なついてたのは お前だけで➡
I guess you were the only one who felt close to them.
連中は
そうでもなかったってことか…｡
They didn't feel the same way...
The Earth's too small for you, after all.
((お前には
地球は狭いんじゃねえの？
これで さよならとしようや))
Let's make this good-bye.
まぁ そんなもんさ…
ｵﾚたちみたいな獣は➡
That's how it goes. Monsters like us... People either use us or hate us. One or the other...
気味悪がられるか
利用されるか 二つに一つ｡
おおかた
ｵﾚたちの暴れっぷり見て➡
In all likelihood, they probably saw us fighting and freaked out.
ﾋﾞﾋﾞっちまったんだろ｡
《星海坊主:すまねえ 神楽…｡
I'm sorry, Kagura.
お前に そんな顔は
二度とさせたくなかった｡
I never wanted to see that expression on your face again.
すべてｵﾚに 責がある｡
It's all my fault.
ｵﾚに罪滅ぼしをさせてくれ｡
Please let me make amends. I won't ever let you feel lonely again.
寂しい思いは 二度とさせねえ｡
日の下で
生きることが できなくとも➡
Even if we cannot live under the rays of the sun, we can live together under the light of the moon.
月の下で
一緒に生きることはできる…｡
神楽… お前は ｵﾚが守る｡
Kagura... I will protect you. And make this up to you...and your mother.
かあちゃんの分までもな…》
(神楽)くさい…｡
You stink...
(新八)あぁ!? 解雇？
You fired her?!
うるせえな！
でけえ声 出すんじゃねえよ!!
Keep it down, will you?
Stop talking so loud. Now look what you did.
あ～あ… 深ﾂﾞﾒしちゃったよ!!
ﾃﾒｴ どうしてくれんだ！
I cut my toenail to the quick. What're you going to do about this?
神楽ちゃんを
解雇したっていうんですか!?
You fired Kagura-chan?!
えっ じゃあ 神楽ちゃん➡
Does that mean Kagura-chan went home together with her father?!
おとうさんと
一緒に帰っちゃったの？
How should I know? She probably did.
知らねえよ… 帰ったんじゃね？
もう １日 経ってるし｡
It's already been a day. She should be happy.
よかったろ？ 金 貯めて
実家帰るとか言ってたのに➡
She always said she was saving up money to go back home. So this saves her the trouble.
手間が省けたんだから…｡
それに お前なぁ
ｶﾞｷとはいえ 女の子が➡
And another thing, it's not right, after all.
野郎の家に あがりこんでる
っていうのはｲｶﾝよ！ やっぱり｡
A little girl shouldn't be living in a strange guy's house anyway.
銀さんだったから
無事だったものの➡
She's lucky she was with me.
最近は ﾛﾘｺﾝとかﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝとかが
流行ってるんだからよ｡
[Lolicon, literally "Lolita Complex," means a fetish for little girls.]
Nowadays you never know when you're gonna meet some sleaze with a lolicon and a polygon.
ｵﾚが親父だったら 殺しにいくね！
その男を…｡
If I were her father, I'd kill the guy.
鼻の穴に指をかけて
背負い投げを…｡
I'd stick my fingers up his nose and throw him across the roo--.
うおりゃあぁぁ～!!
ｲﾀﾞﾀﾞﾀﾞ… とれた！ これ｡
Owwww! You broke it off! You tore my nose off! What'd you do that for?!
絶対 鼻 とれた!!
何しやがんだ～!?
見損ないましたよ 銀さん｡
You disappoint me, Gin-san.
ｱﾝﾀ 神楽ちゃんの気持とか
考えたことあんのかよ？
Haven't you ever thought about Kagura-chan's feelings?
Huh? What's so bad about returning a runaway girl back to her father?
あん？ 家出娘を 親の元に返して
何が悪いんだよ!?
お前 ﾎﾝﾄ ﾊﾞｶな！
ﾀﾞﾒだ… お前 ﾎﾝﾄ ﾀﾞﾒだ!!
You really are stupid! Hopeless! Truly hopeless!
ｺﾗ！ ﾀﾞﾒｶﾞﾈ!! ﾃﾒｴ ﾒｶﾞﾈ割って
ただのﾀﾞﾒにしてやろうか!?
Hey, hopeless specs,
shall I bust those specs of yours and make you just plain "hopeless"?
ｱﾝﾀ 何にも わかってないよ！
You don't understand anything!
You have no idea how much Kagura-chan cherished this place!
神楽ちゃんが どれだけ
ここを 大事に思っていたか！
I won't break even if I'm the last remaining branch.
((私は 最後の一本になっても
折れないね｡
I'll stick with the tree until the very end.
最後まで 木と一緒にいるね！))
神楽ちゃんが どれだけｱﾝﾀを…｡
Kagura-chan thought the world of you...
You don't have to tell me that! We're already living the way we want to.
((言われなくてもなぁ こちとら
とっくに好きに生きてんだよ！
好きで ここに来てんだよ！
We came here because we wanted to.
(２人)好きで
ｱﾝﾀと一緒にいるんだよ!!))
We came here to be with you.
もういい…｡
Forget it.
銀さんが そういうつもりなら
ﾎﾞｸも やめさせてもらいます｡
If that's what you really think, then I'm quitting, too.
仲間だと思ってたのは
ﾎﾞｸらだけだったみたいですね｡
Seems we were the only ones who thought we were friends.
やめたきゃ やめな！
If you want to quit, then quit.
ﾃﾒｴも神楽も こっちから頼んで
来てもらった覚えはねえよ！
I don't remember ever asking you or Kagura to come here.
Ouch...my back...
ｲﾃﾃﾃ… 腰が…｡
ったく 何だってんだ！
どいつもｺｲﾂも…｡
What is it, with all of you...
ん？
なんだ… 文句あんのか？ ｺﾗ｡
ｴｻ抜くぞ！ あん？
What? Got a problem with that? I won't feed you.
If you want to leave, you can go right ahead.
出ていきたきゃ
お前も出ていっていいんだぞ｡
んだよっ そんなとこにいねえよ！
What? You won't find her there.
Tsk, you're a sharp one.
ﾁｯ めざとい野郎だなぁ｡
これで よかったんだよな｡
It's better this way. I don't really know what it's all about, this father-child thing.
ｵﾚも 親子ってのが
どういうもんなのか➡
よく わからねえが｡
これで よかったのさ｡
But it's better this way.
This craft may rock or sway during transport.
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)この機体は 転送中に
揺れることもございます｡
ｼｰﾄﾍﾞﾙﾄを しっかり腰に巻き➡
Please fasten your seatbelts securely around...
ﾗﾝﾌﾟが消えるまでは
座席を お立ちになりませんよう➡
your waist and please remain seated until the light goes out.
お願い申し上げます｡
Sir, you can't. This ship will be leaving shortly.
(CA)お客様 困ります！
当機は まもなく出航しますので➡
安定空域に達するまで
座席に座っていただかないと！
You must remain seated until we reach stable airspace.
(星海坊主)ｲﾔｲﾔ ｲﾔ… ﾑﾘ！
これ ﾑﾘ!!
No, no, no, There's a little ship in my bowels that's about to take off too!
ｵﾚの中の船も出航するって｡
ﾎﾞﾝﾎﾞﾔｰｼﾞｭ！
Bon voyage!
No, sir, that was not funny.
(CA)いや 全然うまくありません
お客様｡
I'm telling you, I can't! Would it be funnier if I crap in my pants?!
(星海坊主)ﾑﾘだって もらすぞ
今ここで もらすぞ！
ｱﾃﾝｼｮﾝ ｳﾝｺ ﾌﾟﾘ～ｽﾞ！
お客様 全然うまくありません！
Right here, right now!
Sir, please stop trying to be funny!
My muscles are losing control of the situation! They're losing it!
(星海坊主)括約筋が 活躍せん！
(水音)
(ﾊﾀ皇子)あっ 出た…｡
...ahh...it came out.
(じい)くらぁ～！
ﾁｬｷﾁｬｷ 働かんかい ｸｿがぁ!!
Get with it! Work faster, dammit!
そこの荷物は ここ！
あれは そこ!!
That container goes here! That goes there!
そこ あれ！
あれは何 ここは どこ!?
That one, there! What is this place?
(整備員)いや
貨物倉庫なんですけど｡
This is the luggage bay.
Who is that bossy old man?
なんだよ あのｼﾞｼﾞｲ 偉そうに｡
He's, you know, a butler for that prince.
(整備員)あれだよ あれ
央国星の皇子｡
The idiotic prince of the Midland Star.
あのﾊﾞｶ皇子の従者らしいよ｡
So all this creepy cargo belongs to that prince?
(整備員)じゃあ この
気味悪い荷物も あの皇子の？
It's a collection of terrible taste. He's got to be dumb... Look at this stuff...
(整備員)趣味悪いｺﾚｸｼｮﾝだなぁ｡
ｳﾜｻどおりの ﾊﾞｶ皇子らしいや｡
Be careful with that! These are all the Prince's treasures.
丁重に扱えよ
これらは すべて皇子の宝物だ｡
ｷｽﾞ１つでも つけたら ｷｻﾏら➡
If you put so much as a scratch on them, I'll tear you limb from limb, I will!
身も心も
ｷｽﾞだらけにしてやるからな｡
この じいがよ｡
へ～い！
All right.
じゃあ ｵﾚは
とりあえず戻るけどよ｡
Okay, I'm going back to my seat now.
But if you insult me behind my back, I swear I'll break your necks!
ｵﾚが いなくなったあとに
悪口とか言ったら➡
ﾏｼﾞ ぶっ殺すから気をつけろよ｡
わぁ～っ！
(２人)えぇ～っ!?
What?!
Hey! What've you done to the Prince's treasure?!
(整備員)ちょっと！
なにしてんですかぁ｡
皇子の宝物を！
Tsk, who put this junk in my way!
(じい)ﾁｯ ｼﾞｬﾏくせえな ｶﾞﾗｸﾀが！
(整備員)ｼﾞｬﾏくさいって言ったよ！
皇子の宝物 ｶﾞﾗｸﾀって言った!!
He said junk! He called the Prince's treasure junk!
ｶﾞﾀｶﾞﾀ騒ぐんじゃねえ｡
Stop making a scene. He's not going to notice one piece of junk missing, you ass!
こんなｺﾞﾐ １つくらい
なくなったところで➡
ﾊﾞﾚねえよ ｸｿが！
Old man, you're insane.
(整備員)ｼﾞｼﾞｲ ｵﾒｴ
言ってること ﾑﾁｬｸﾁｬだから！
Never mind. Hurry and clean this up. There'll be hell to pay if that idiot finds out.
(じい)いいから早く片づけろ｡
ﾊﾞｶにﾊﾞﾚたら ことだ｡
ﾓｯﾌﾟ ﾓｯﾌﾟ持ってこい… ん？
A mop... Bring a mop. Huh?
Odd... Hey, where is the thing that was inside this?
(じい)あれっ おい
これに入ってた中身 どこいった？
What? How would we know? Was there something inside?
(整備員)え？ 知りませんよ｡
中に 何か入ってたんですか？
(じい)そこにあるのと
似たようなのが➡
There should've been something similar to those things.
入ってたはずなんだが｡
What? A monster like these?!
(整備員)えっ こんなﾊﾞｹﾓﾝが!?
That's odd. How could a corpse disappear by itself?
おかしいな
ただの死骸が ひとりでに？
ん？
Just a minute... You can't go in there.
(係員)ちょっ ﾀﾞﾒですってば！
お客様 こっから先は
ﾁｹｯﾄがないと通れないの！
Sir, you can't go through here without a ticket!
We'll call the police!
(係員)警察 呼びますよ！
Wait! Listen! Listen to me!
待って！
話を 話を聞いてください!!
あの あれ 恋人が！
My, uh, girlfriend!
My girlfriend was kidnapped by an old guy with a hairdo like barcode
ﾎﾞｸの恋人が
ﾊﾞｰｺｰﾄﾞの おっさんにとられて➡
and the two of them are trying to run off on their honeymoon.
２人で ﾊﾈﾑｰﾝ
決め込もうとしてるんです｡
You expect me to believe you have a girlfriend.
ｳｿをつけぇ！
ｷﾐは 彼女いなさそうだぞ｡
彼女いない歴 16年そうだぞ！
You look like you haven't had a girlfriend for 16 years!
どういう意味だ それぇ！
なんで歳まで われてんだぁ!!
And what the hell is that supposed to mean?! How do you know my age?
あ～ ｳｿｳｿ 今のは
ちょっと見栄 はっちゃいました｡
Okay, I lied, I lied.
I was just trying to make myself look good.
実は その ﾊﾞｰｺｰﾄﾞは ﾎﾞｸの父親で➡
The truth is, the barcode guy is my father.
援交にﾊﾏｯて 家庭放り出して➡
He was tricked by a young girl looking for a sugar daddy and dumped his family.
女の子と
心中しようとしてるんです｡
Now he's about to commit suicide with her.
Don't lie to me! You look like your father already died!
ｳｿをつけぇ！ ｷﾐは
父親は死んでるっぽいぞ なんか!!
だから なんで われてんの～
なんで知ってんだよぉ！
How did you know? How come you know that?
おわぁ～！
Kagura-chan.
《神楽ちゃん｡
I don't know what kind of life you led before.
ﾎﾞｸはｷﾐが どんな人生を
送ってきたかなんて知らない｡
ｷﾐが お父さんを
どう思ってるかなんて 知らない｡
And I don't know how you feel about your father.
でも…｡
But, I do know how much you loved Odd Jobs.
ｷﾐが どれだけ 万事屋が
好きかってことは知ってるよ｡
ｷﾐがどれだけ 銀さんを
大切に思ってるか 知ってるよ｡
I know how much you cherished Gin-san.
知ってるんだ｡ だって…》
I know, because...
(２人)うおぉ～！
I feel the same!
《ﾎﾞｸもｷﾐと 同じだから！》
I'm sorry!
すいませ～ん！
《神楽:このまま
ずっと ３人一緒…｡
The three of us, together forever... I realize it would be impossible.
そんなことは ﾑﾘだなんて
わかってる｡
Someday... I knew we'd have to part.
きっと いつか別れのときが
くるのは わかってる｡
But right now...
でも 今は…》
Man, that was an awful experience. Let me tell you about it, Kagura-chan.
あ～ ひどい目に遭った｡
聞いてくれよ 神楽ちゃん
神楽ちゃ…｡
Kagura-cha...
《神楽:まだ 今は…》
Right now, I still...
(客)お… おいっ なんだ あれ！
Hey... Hey! What is that?!
(客)あれ 人だ！
あんな所に人がいるぞ!!
It's a man! There's a man on the ladder!
Wait! Wait!
待って！ 待ってよ～!!
Kagura-chan!! Where are you going?!
神楽ちゃん どこ行くんだぁ！
ﾎﾞｸら ３人揃って万事屋だろぉ！
Odd Jobs means the three of us! Together!
Whatever Gin said to you, ignore him! He's a moron!
ﾊﾞｶに 何言われたか知らないけど➡
あんなのの言うこと
聞かなくていいって！
He doesn't even pay you a decent wage!
給料も ﾛｸに払わないんだから！
I can't handle that idiot by myself! I need you back at Odd Jobs with me!
ﾎﾞｸ１人じゃ
あのﾊﾞｶは 手に負えないよ！
帰るなよ！
まだ一緒に万事屋で働こうよ!!
That nimrod! What a stupid thing to do!
あの野郎 なんてﾊﾞｶなﾏﾈを｡
Shinpachi...
(神楽)新八…｡
新八…｡
Shinpachi.
Shinpa...
新ぱ…｡
(客たちの悲鳴)
Pappy!
ﾊﾟﾋﾟｰ！
ｺｲﾂぁ…｡
You...
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)緊急警報 緊急警報！
Emergency alarm! Emergency alarm!
７番ｹﾞｰﾄで 異常発生！
７番ｹﾞｰﾄで異常発生!!
We have an emergency at Gate 7!
All personnel, report to your posts immediately.
係の者は 速やかに所定の位置に｡
繰り返す！
We repeat: all personnel, report to your posts immediately.
係の者は 速やかに所定の位置に！
なんじゃ ありゃ～！
What is that thing?!
♪♪～
At least it's not coming this way! It's not coming this way, is it?
あれっ こっち来てない!?
ｳｿｯ こっち来てない!?
ﾔﾊﾞｲ！ こっち来てない!?
Oh god! It's coming this way!
わあぁ～っ！
Alien? Never heard the word. Sounds like a candy shop.
えいりあん？ 知らねえな｡
お菓子屋みたいな名前しやがって｡
栄利庵か？ あん？
Is that Eirian?
[Eirian]
Well, we're not handing Earth over to the likes of you, bozos.
言っとくけどよぅ 地球は
ﾃﾒｴらなんかに渡さねえから｡
Earth belongs to us yakuza!
地球はﾜｼら やくざのもんじゃい！
What? You'll what...? Uh...um... That's cruel.
(定春)ﾜﾝｯ！
なんだとぅ｡
お前 そんなことを…
あの あれ… ひどいぞ｡
You're, you know what, if you do that sort of thing, uh...
お前 あれだぞ
そんなことしたら あの…｡
That's so wrong!
ﾀﾞﾒだぞぉ～！
The battle of... Alien vs. Yakuza!
(長谷川)かくして
えいりあんと やくざ➡
And so the battle for a planet begins!
地球存亡をかけた戦いが
始まるわけでございます！
はたして 地球の運命は？
What will be the fate of Earth?
続きは ぜひ劇場のほうで！
You can see the rest of this story in the theater.
No one's coming! Who'd want to come?!
って来るかぁ！ 誰が来るかぁ
こんな呼び込みで!!
Who's gonna fall for this lame teaser?! Look at you losers!
なに このｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞ感！
Were you even listening at the meeting?
だから 打ち合わせ
ちゃんと聞けって言ったんだよ！
What's up with "That's so wrong"? What's wrong is you guys!
｢ﾀﾞﾒだぞぉ～！｣って なんだ？
ﾀﾞﾒなのは お前たちだ｡
You think standing there frozen is gonna impress me?
って いつまで一時停止してんだ！
もう いいんだよ！
You're serious only about the part that doesn't matter!
どうでもいいことだけ
ﾏｼﾞﾒなんだな！ もう｡
(長谷川)ﾌﾟﾊ～ｯ ったく➡
And after I went through the trouble to get you work.
せっかく 人が
仕事 まわしてやってんのによぉ｡
Forget it, you guys. Just shut up and hold the damned flags.
もういいから お前ら
黙って 旗持って立ってろ｡
(定春の きばる声)
定春君➡
Sadaharu-kun, keep your butt quiet, too, please.
ｹﾂのほうも 無言で頼む｡
Hey, Gin-san, what happened to the others?
おい銀さん
そういや ｱｲﾂらどうした？
影の薄いﾒｶﾞﾈ君と 怪力娘｡
That nondescript guy with the glasses and that China girl? With their help, it would be...
人手がいりゃあ もう少し…｡
How would I know. I can do anything myself even if they aren't around.
知るかよ あんなのいなくたって➡
ｵﾚ １人で なんだってできんだよ｡
Why? Because Gin-san is very versatile.
なぜなら銀さん
とっても器用だから！
おいおい ｻﾗｯとｵﾚの器用の概念
覆すんじゃねえよ｡
Hey, don't completely ruin my image of "versatile."
Hey, Hasegawa-san, the boss is calling for you.
(おばちゃん)ちょっと ちょっと
長谷川さん｡
社長が呼んでるけど｡
ｳｿ  やべえ｡
What? This isn't good. He said if we didn't show results, he'd fire us on the spot.
結果 出さねえと
即ｸﾋﾞって言ってたからな｡
(おばちゃん)呼び込みなんて
やっても 今日はﾑﾀﾞだよ｡
No point bringing in a crowd today. Nobody's gonna want to come and see fake aliens.
ちょっと こっち来な！
わざわざ 作りもんのえいりあん
なんか 見にこなくても➡
You see?
ほらぁ 本物のえいりあんが
大騒ぎ 起こしてんだから｡
People got a real alien to worry about.
Hey, where is that? Is that the terminal?
おいおい なんだこりゃ？
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙか？
なんか 船に➡
Seems a huge alien took over a ship and caused an accident.
でっかいえいりあんが とりついて
事故 起こしたらしいよ｡
Can we get our camera closer?
(結野ｱﾅ)あの…
もっと ｶﾒﾗ寄れませんか？
え～
皆さん 見えますでしょうか？
I'm sorry, uh...can you see it, everyone?
謎の生物によって➡
A mysterious creature has caused an accident involving a ship inside the terminal.
現在 １艘の船が
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙ内で 事故を起こし➡
You can see the nose of the crashed spaceship where it breached the terminal wall.
機体の一部が
壁面から突き出た状態です｡
There is concern for the safety of the passengers.
It's frightening.
(おばちゃん)いやぁ 怖いわ…｡
But what is this sinister creature?
(結野ｱﾅ)あの まがまがしい生物は
いったい 何なのでしょう？
(結野ｱﾅ)ん？ あれ… 人影!?
Huh? Just a minute... Is that a person?
I'm positive. It is a man! A man!
(結野ｱﾅ)間違いない！
人です！ 人が…｡
Huh? A young girl?!
(結野ｱﾅ)えっ 女の子？
な なんということでしょう！
Oh my gosh. It's a young girl!
(結野ｱﾅ)少女が… １人の少女が
船の甲板で 謎の生物を相手に…！
A lone young girl is on the spaceship's hull...
and it looks as if she's fighting
お おい…｡
H-Hey, Gin-san... That's...!
I don't believe it. Is she human?!
銀さん あれ！ …あれ？
(星海坊主)おい… おい…｡
Hey... Hey...pull yourself together, lad. Hey.
(星海坊主)
しっかりしろ 坊主｡ おい｡
あれ？ ここは 冥土ですか？
Am I in the world of the dead?
花畑じゃなくて
焼け野原が見える｡
I don't see gardens of flowers. I see a burnt plain.
誰の頭が 焼け野原？
Whose head are you calling a burnt plain?
You want to go to hell? You want to live happily forever in a flower garden?
花畑 行くか？
花畑で 永遠に 楽しく暮らすか？
星海坊主さん…｡
Umibozu-san?
Quickly, get outta here, lad. Or you'll be killed.
さっさと お前も逃げろ 坊主｡
死ぬぞ｡
(星海坊主)まさか
野郎が生きてやがったとは…｡
Who'd have thought it'd still be alive?
(星海坊主)しかし
どこで ご馳走になったのか➡
And where'd he eat enough to get that big?
あんな でかくなりやがって…｡
I should've made sure he was dead.
ｵﾚとしたことが ﾂﾒが甘かったな｡
It'll engulf this place soon. Get going.
じき ここも呑まれるぞ｡
さっさと行け｡
What about you, Baldy?
坊主さんは？
坊主さんって なに？
Who the hell are you calling "Baldy", boy?
ねぇ 大の大人に 坊主さん？
(星海坊主)神楽ちゃんの姿が
見当たらねえ｡
I don't see Kagura-chan.
(星海坊主)ｱｲﾂのことだ…
他の連中を気遣って➡
Knowing her, she probably remained on the ship to look after the others.
船に残ってるかもしれねえ｡
Wait.
待って ﾎﾞｸも行きます｡
I'm coming too. I just can't leave...Kagura-chan there.
神楽ちゃんは… ほっとけない｡
You'll get in my way. Go home.
(星海坊主)ｼﾞｬﾏだ 帰れ｡
From here on, it's a battlefield. Weak life forms like you will only be a liability.
こっから ここは 戦場だ｡
ﾃﾒｴらみてえな ひ弱な生き物に
いられたら 迷惑なんだよ｡
ここは ｵﾚたちの居場所だ｡
This is where we belong.
《なんて目だ…》
Those eyes.
でも ﾎﾞｸは！
But I...
(星海坊主)ｵﾚたちの生きる場所は
違う と言ってんだ｡
I told you: we live in a different world.
これ以上 神楽に関わるな｡
Forget about Kagura. You'll only make her unhappy.
これ以上 神楽を苦しめるな｡
Do you think people can change so easily?
(星海坊主)人が 簡単に変われると
思っているのか？
《星海坊主:そうさ…
変われるものか｡
No, people can't change.
もがいても もがいても
結局 変われやしなかった｡
She struggled and struggled, but in the end, she couldn't change.
All the pain of trying to change...was just that. Pain.
何にも
変えることなんてできなかった｡
苦しいだけなら いっそ…》
(ﾊﾀ/じい)うわぁ～っ!!
ぎゃあ～っ!!
助けてくれ～!!
Help us!
早く！ こっちｱﾙ!!
Quickly! This way!
♪♪～
(結野ｱﾅ)見てください 皆さん！
There it is! The Alien has exploded in size!
謎の生物が
急激に 巨大化しております！
This is dangerous. Way too dangerous!
(結野ｱﾅ)これは 危険です｡
これは 危険すぎです！
(結野ｱﾅ)私も さすがに
逃げたくなってまいりました！
Even I feel like running away.
It's dangerous. Clear out of here!
(沖田)おぅ 危ないぜ｡
どいときな｡
Ack! It's the Shinsengumi. The guardians of Edo,
(結野ｱﾅ)あっ 真選組です！
我らが 江戸の守護者➡
武装警察 真選組が
駆けつけてくれました！
The Shinsengumi armed police have arrived on the scene.
もう大丈夫！
We'll be fine now.
(沖田)えいりあ～ん
お前は 完全に包囲されている｡
Alien, you are completely surrounded. Give yourself up quietly.
おとなしく投降しなさ～い｡
えっ ちょっと
なにやってるんですか？
Huh? What are you doing?
(沖田)故郷のお母さんも
泣いてるぞ｡
Your mother back in your hometown is crying!
She didn't raise you to be this kind of alien.
こんな えいりあんにするために
産んだんじゃないってな｡
Right, Mom?
(沖田)ねぇ お母さん
何か言ってやってください｡
Say something.
(結野ｱﾅ)えっ ﾏｼﾞで？ ｳｿ…｡
What? Are you serious?! I don't believe this!
Do you know what your father said just before he died?
(近藤)お父さん 最後に何て言って
死んでいったか ｱﾝﾀに わかる!?
お父さんね
最後まで ｱﾝﾀのこと…！
Until the very end, Daddy cared only about you.
なにしてんの ｱﾝﾀら！
What the hell are you guys doing?!
へっ？ ｷｬｰｯ!!
(沖田)ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙは
幕府の重要建築物に➡
The Bakufu gave this Terminal "Architectural Landmark" status.
指定されてるんでぇ｡
許可なく発砲すれば➡
If we start shooting, It'll be our heads that roll.
こっちのｸﾋﾞがとぶ｡
言ってる場合ですか！
This is no time for that! All our heads will roll if you don't do something!
ここで 本物のｸﾋﾞ
とばされたいんですか!?
Hey! If you don't get away quickly, you'll get killed!
(土方)お～い 早く逃げねえと
死ぬぞ ﾃﾒｴら｡
(結野ｱﾅ)なんなの!?
一般市民 差し置いて➡
What is it with you?
You leave the press to die while you escape in a patrol car?!
ﾊﾟﾄｶｰで逃げてんの!?
なに この人たち！
What's with you people?!
I never imagined that thing would still be alive.
しかし あれが
まだ生きてたとはねぇ｡
どういう経緯で ここに来たのか
知らねえが➡
I don't know how it got here, but it's turned into a major disaster.
えれえことになったもんだ｡
(土方)どうやら 奴さん
想像以上に しぶというえに➡
Seems it's tougher than we imagined.
食ったら食っただけ でかくなる
やっかいなﾔﾂらしいぜ｡
Apparently, the more it eats, the bigger it gets. And it eats energy.
Which makes it especially bad news that it's making the terminal its nest.
(土方)しかも 運の悪いことに
今度の住まいは ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙときた｡
(土方)あれは 膨大なｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰを
使って 船を転送する➡
Incredible amounts of energy pump through this place to teleport ships.
いわば ｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰのﾎﾟﾝﾌﾟ｡
(土方)ﾔﾂの急成長は
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙに流れる➡
This thing's sudden growth is because it's consuming the immense energy flowing though the terminal.
強大なｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰそのものを
食らったせいだ｡
(土方)やべえな… このままじゃ
江戸は食い尽くされるぞ｡
This is bad. At this rate, Edo will be devoured.
ﾃﾒｴ なに撮ってんだ！
What're you shooting?!
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)ｲﾃﾃｯ ｱﾀﾞｯ！
Ow ow ow ow!
(女)いやぁ 怖いわぁ｡
I'm scared!
What's going to happen to Edo?
(男)おいおい
どうなっちまうんだ 江戸は｡
What's going to happen to me? I'm unemployed again.
どうなっちまうんだ ｵﾚは｡
また 無職になっちまった｡
いっそ
江戸なんて滅んじまえば…｡
Why should I care if Edo gets destroyed?
Ack! What's that?!
(結野ｱﾅ)なんでしょうか あれは！
逃げ惑う人々を押し切って➡
Something's coming this way...flying past the fleeing crowd.
何かが こちらへ…｡
(結野ｱﾅ)あれは… 犬？
Is that a...dog?
No...a samurai?!
(結野ｱﾅ)いや… 侍!?
Boss?!
旦那！
お前 なに…!?
What're you...?!
あっ これ ｶﾒﾗ？ これ ｶﾒﾗ？
Is this a TV camera? A camera?
Um... "Alien vs. Yakuza," the movie...
え～と
映画 『えいりあん VS やくざ』！
Playing in theaters now. Don't miss it.
絶賛 上映中｡ 観にきてね｡
What just happened?! Who is that mysterious man?!
(結野ｱﾅ)なんなんですか
あの 謎の人物は!!
(結野ｱﾅ)ちょっと！
危ないですって ちょっと～！
Wait! It's dangerous!
Gin-san, you're too late. We've already been fired.
《銀さん もう遅い…｡
もう ｸﾋﾞになっちゃったから…》
神楽ちゃ～ん!! どこ行った!?
Kagura-chan!
Where are you?! Pappy's right here!
(星海坊主)お父さんは ここだぞ!!
This is bad.
ｺｲﾂは やばいな…｡
This is the toughest fight since that time I eradicated the giant cockroach.
(星海坊主)８年前の
巨大ｺﾞｷﾌﾞﾘ退治以来の大ﾋﾟﾝﾁだ｡
No, since the fight I had with the wife when we were newlyweds.
いや 新婚の頃 かあちゃんと
ｹﾝｶしたとき以来のﾋﾟﾝﾁだ｡
Oh, are you guys hurt or just taking a dump?
(星海坊主)お前は ｳﾝｺしてた
課長っぽい人｡ おい 大丈夫か？
(星海坊主)しっかりしろ｡
おい 係長｡
Hang in there, assistant manager.
おい なんで ﾜﾝﾗﾝｸ下げた？
(星海坊主)大丈夫か？
Hey, what's with the demotion?
Are you all right? How'd you get that thing on your forehead?
おでこの それ どうした？
えいりあんに やられたのか？
Did the alien do that to you?
These are the marks of our exalted people!! Fool!!
ｹｶﾞで こんなんなるか！
最初から ついてんだよ！
生まれたときから
こんなんなんだよ！
(星海坊主)この傘…｡
Her umbrella...
おい 神楽を見たのか！
見ただろ!?
Hey, have you seen Kagura?! You saw her, didn't you?
ｵﾚと そっくりな
目のｸﾘｯとした かわいい女の子!!
A cute girl with big round eyes that look exactly like mine!
I'm not responsible! I'm not responsible! It's not my fault!
ﾜﾜﾜ… ﾜｼは知らん｡ ﾜｼは知らんぞ｡
ﾜｼは悪くない｡
It's the Prince's fault! It's because he keeps a collection of monsters!
皇子が悪いんだ！ こんなﾊﾞｹﾓﾉ
ｺﾚｸｼｮﾝしようとするから！
What? It's not my fault!
それを言うなら えいりあんの
死亡を確認しなかった➡
The customs people should have checked to make sure it was dead!
入管の連中が…｡
えぇい!!
でやぁ～っ！
旦那！
野郎 死ぬつもりか!?
Boss!
That fool! Does he want to get killed?!
定春 散歩の時間だ！
Sadaharu, time for your walk.
今日は どこで ｸｿたれようが
じゃれようが ﾌﾘｰﾀﾞﾑだ｡
Today, you're free to poop or play wherever you want. You can go wild.
めいっぱい暴れな！
いくぜぇ～っ！
Let's go!
あり？
What?
(星海坊主)でぇい!!
She's a girl with refined facial features who looks just like me. Have you seen her?
(星海坊主)ｵﾚとそっくりな
気品ある顔立ちの➡
女の子なんだけどさ 知らない？
知ってる｡
I have. I saw a cute girl who looks like you!
ｱﾝﾀとそっくりな かわいい女の子｡
どこかの星の王女様ですか？
Is she a queen of some planet? She was a truly cute darling of a girl.
あれは ﾎﾝﾄかわいい
珠のような女の子｡
You should've told me! Please...
それを言えって言ってんの｡
頼むよ おい｡ おじさん
いい歳して 短気だから｡
I'm an old man and I'm impatient.
あ… あっち｡
でも もう…➡
Over there.
But it's too...
私らを助けて ﾊﾞｹﾓﾉに…｡
She rescued us, but the monster...
Kagura!
(星海坊主)神楽～っ!!
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
Oh my! Gin-san was eaten by the alien!
And Baldy is hurt trying to protect the injured Kagura-chan.
Isn't that the Bakufu's battleship?!
If she fires with all cannons, everyone will be killed.
The next episode: "You Know What Happens if You Pee on a Worm."
[A giant alien puts Edo on the brink of destruction.]
[What is the fate of Kagura, who is on the brink of death?! And where is Gintoki?!]
♬～
(ﾃｰﾏ音楽)